Kristy Nerhaugen, M.L.S.

kristynerhaugen@gmail.com | (218)-341-1271 | Duluth, MN

Github: https://github.com/KristyNerhaugen

Portfolio: https://kristynerhaugen.github.io/kn-react-portfolio/LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/kristy-nerhaugen-a7a868252

Full stack web developer with a background in Library Science. Recently obtained a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Minnesota. Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, and more. Experienced leader with strong organization, communication, and collaboration abilities. Coming from a public service background, putting people first and hoping to make the web more accessible through a better user experience.

Skills

Technologies: GitHub, VS Code, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, GraphQL, MySQL, NoSQL, React,

MongoDB, Express.js, Insomnia

Concepts: Object-oriented programming, object-relational mapping, model-view-controller

Skills: Organized, detail oriented, strong leader, clear communicator

Projects

Where Were You When

Deployed Site: https://where-were-you-when.herokuapp.com/

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/McAmy2001/Where-Were-You-When

Where Were You When is a MERN stack, single page application that allows a user to record and save their memories. The user can view their own past memories and will be reminded of a memory on the same date that they are using the application.

P.A.R.K.O.U.R.

Deployed Site: https://parkour-review.herokuapp.com/

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/KristyNerhaugen/playground-rating-app

PARKOUR is an app designed to help parents and caregivers easily find and give reviews about parks and playgrounds. Once the user creates an account, they have the ability to write, edit and delete their own reviews. They can also comment on other reviews. If the user doesn't want to make an account, they can still view park and playground reviews without the ability to comment or leave their own review.

Boozy Books

Deployed Site: https://github.com/KristyNerhaugen/Boozy-Books GitHub Repository: https://nickschenck.github.io/Book-Nook/

Boozy Books is an application for book and drink lovers. This application uses two server side APIs, Google Books API and the Cocktail DB API to allow users to search for books and to discover new drinks to pair with books. Users can also store book titles in the To Be Read list that saves to the page and persists using client-side storage.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate October 2022

University of Minnesota

Master of Library Science 2014

School of Informatics and Computing, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Bachelor of Arts 2011

English Major, Political Science Minor, Gustavus Adolphus College, St. Peter, MN Sigma Tau Delta English Honor Society 2011 Gustavus Diversity Honors Award Recipient

Experience

Librarian II: Youth Services Coordinator June 2016 - April 2022

Duluth Public Library, Duluth, MN

- Successfully lead youth services work group of 8 staff members
- Responsible for scheduling, training, onboarding, and team building
- Coordinated all year-long reading programs
- Lead the Youth Services programming team for all in person and passive programming
- Responsible for overseeing programming budget
- Site Supervisor for Summer True North AmeriCorps Member
- Implemented Beanstack software, lead the library's Beanstack team, and trained staff on Beanstack
- Facilitated department meetings, lead library-wide programming committee
- Coordinated all Minnesota Legacy grant funded programming for the library

Librarian I August 2014 - June 2016

Duluth Public Library, Duluth, MN

- Staffed the Youth Services Desk: provide patron assistance, reference, and reader's
- advisory
- Ordered and maintain Children's DVD and CD Collections
- Coordinated Children's and Teen Summer and Winter Reading Programs
- Planned and assist with all children's and young adult programming, including storytimes and passive programs

Evening and Weekend Supervisor August 2013 - May 2014

Neal-Marshall Black Culture Center Library, Bloomington, IN

- Responsible for selecting, reviewing, and purchasing materials for the library's collection
- Staffed public service desk, performed circulation duties and reference services
- Supervised Student Library Assistants
- Assisted with shelving and shelf reading when needed

Student Library Assistant August 2012 - June 2013

Neal-Marshall Black Culture Center Library, Bloomington, IN

- Staffed public service desk, performing circulation duties and reference services
- Assisted with shelving and shelf reading

Additional Experience

Elementary Literacy Tutor, Minnesota Reading Corps, AmeriCorps, Duluth, MN